我终于来到了这里
Oh, I'm finally here.
这一直是我的梦想
Oh, this has been my dream
从我看过《一个美国人在巴黎》后就如此了
ever since I saw "An American in Paris."
影响我的电影是《天使爱美丽》
For me, it was "Amélie."
我当年还强迫我妈给我剪女主同款发型
I made my mom give me that haircut.
情人节快乐 宝贝
Happy Valentine's Day, mon cheri.
基佬巴黎[美好巴黎]
Ah, gay Paree.
瞧 我就说克莱尔肯定会用这个哏吐槽
See, I told you it would be Claire.
我押的是杰会吐槽
I had my money on Jay.
抱歉 姑娘们
Sorry, ladies,
我心情太好不想吐槽
I'm in too good a mood.
没什么大事
It's no big deal.
我只是在今年的国际衣柜博览会上
I'm getting a lifetime achievement award
获得了终身成就奖
at this year's Expo Internationale du Closet.
他们怎么不把最后一个词也翻成法语
Why don't they translate the last word?
我相信法语里肯定有"衣柜"这个词吧
I'm sure they have a word for closet.
他们是法国人
They're French.
或许是没翻到最后一个词 就习惯性罢工了
Maybe they went on strike before they got to the end.
普里契特先生 欢迎来到皇冠广场酒店
Monsieur Pritchett, welcome to the Crowne Plaza.
我是伯纳德·布斯
I am Bernard Busse,
国际衣柜行会的主席
president of the International Closet Guild.
么么
Mwah!
老天 他还发出恶心的声音
Oh, God. He made the sound.
这位女士根本无需介绍
And this woman needs no introduction.
你跟杰在邮件中形容的一样美
You are just as beautiful as Jay described in his e-mail.
很高兴见到你 斯黛拉
It's a pleasure to meet you, Stella.
不 不 这是我妻子歌洛莉亚
Oh, no, no. This is my wife, Gloria.
我本来想在邮件中提到你的 但一写就太长了
I-I put you in the e-mail, but then it was too long.
希望在一小时后的鸡尾酒招待会上见到二位
I hope to see you both at the cocktail reception in an hour.
待会儿见
A bientot.
再见[西语]
Adios.
你可真会乱上添乱 还掺杂第三种语言
'Cause that's what we need. A third language.
我们有一小时的时间 去观光吧
We have an hour. We should go sightseeing.
-或许去看看巴黎圣母院 -不了 谢谢
- Maybe check out Notre Dame. - No, thank you.
我曾见过它辉煌的样子
I saw it back in the day,
而非如今这般空有壳没有魂
before it was a shell of itself.
再去看一次 只会让我郁闷难受
Seeing it again would only depress me.
是啊 我懂你的意思
Yeah, I know what you mean.
所以我现在都没法去西尔斯百货购物了[实则已破产倒闭]
That's why I can't shop at Sears.
曼尼 你去帮我们办理登记入住吧
Manny, why don't you go and check us in
因为你让整个家族蒙羞
since you disgraced this family
你竟然学法语 而不是西班牙语
by learning French instead of Spanish.
一定要拿下他们承诺我的那个房间
And get that room that they promised me.
显然某个伯爵曾在那里睡过
Apparently some earl once slept there.
我们太为你骄傲了 爸
We're so proud of you, Dad.
谢谢 我只希望我父亲能在此看到这一幕
Thanks. I only wish my old man could be here to see this.
说起来也好笑
You know, it's funny.
他参与过诺曼底登陆战
He stormed the beaches of Normandy,
我却要领取衣柜界的大奖了
and I'm getting a closet award.
后辈不断超越祖辈的光辉
We keep topping each other.
谁知道小乔能有怎样伟大的成就呢
Who knows what Joe will do?
你有什么安排
Hey, w-what are you doing now?
你懂的 情人节嘛
Well, you know, it's Valentine's Day,
所以我打算跟我丈夫一起
so I think I'm gonna enjoy
享受这世上最浪漫的城市
the most romantic city in the world with my husband.
抱歉
Sorry.
菲尔去不成巴黎 因为他有工作要忙
Phil can't come to Paris because he has to work.
虽然很扫兴 但我一个人也会玩得很开心
It stinks, but I am still gonna have so much fun
因为我打算重游
visiting all my favorite places
当年在那里短期留学时最爱的地方
from the semester I spent there in college.
房地产紧急事件
Real-estate emergency.
经纪人和客户间的保密协议
Um, broker/client confidentiality
禁止我谈论具体事宜
fobids me from discussing it.
我见过的那些事...
The stuff I've seen...
你们不会想知道的
You do not want to know.
没错
Correct.
如果你愿意
Look, if you want,
并且当电灯泡也不会让你觉得太尴尬 或许...
and you don't feel too awkward about being a third wheel, maybe --
米奇尔竟因可怜我而相邀
Pity invite from Mitchell?
真是风水轮流转啊
How the tables have turned.
不了 谢谢
No, merci.
我要去找我最爱的咖啡厅
I'm gonna go find my favorite cafe,
喝一杯葡萄酒 不为自己独自一人而伤悲
have a glass of wine, and try not to be sad that I'm all alone.
好吧 祝你玩得开心
Okay, great. Have fun.
再见
Bye.
我听说这里的面包
You know, I heard the bread here
比我们国家的那种要健康些
is healthier than the kind we have back home.
那怎么可能呢 面包就是面包啊
Well, how is that possible? Bread is bread.
按常理是这样 但实际上这里的谷物...
You would think, but it's actually the way that the grain is, um --
不对 是因为烤箱...
No, no, it's -- It's the way that the -- the ovens --
好吧 反正我要趁在这里吃很多面包
Okay, look, I'm gonna have a lot of bread while we're here.
它们必须得好
I need it to be okay.
我真的很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我好像有点倒不过来时差
I think I'm jet-lagged.
不如这样吧 我去睡个觉
You know what? I might take a nap
你自己出去游玩探索吧
while you go out and explore.
是什么声音啊 你的箱子怎么会发出声响
What was that? W-Why did your bag honk?
可能是电话声吧 这里的电话铃声都是那种的
I think that was a phone. You know, that's how they ring here.
谁快接一下电话啊 有人吗 快
Will somebody answer that? Hmm? Hmm?
别生气
Don't be mad.
菲茨宝
Fizbo?
你说你的箱子装不下我的毛衣
My sweaters were too bulky to pack,
但却能装得下菲茨宝装备
but Fizbo made the cut?
拜托 你知道我一直以来都有一个梦想
Oh, come on. You know it's always been my dream to --
就是将菲茨宝的魔力带到法国街头
to bring the magic of Fizbo to the streets of Paris.
你并不是倒不过来时差
You're not jet-lagged.
你是打算偷偷溜出去 在街上"丑来丑去"
You were gonna sneak out and go clown around.
你知道这个说法不对 是"扮小丑逗乐"
You know that's not how we say it. It's "Clown about."
我真不敢相信你竟然对我撒谎了
I-I can't believe you lied to me.
我也不敢相信我还得对你撒谎才行
Well, I can't believe I had to.
大多数小丑的配偶都是非常支持他们的
You know, most clowns have spouses that are supportive.
我才不信大多数小丑能有配偶
I'm not convinced most clowns have spouses.
克莱尔即将见到
Claire was about to meet
克莱夫·比克斯比的法国表哥 克劳德
Clive Bixby's French cousin, Claude.
计划很简单
The plan was simple enough.
我只需捏造一个工作上的紧急事件
All I did was create a fake work emergency
然后在克莱尔最爱的咖啡厅等她
and wait for Claire at her favorite cafe.
欢迎来到法国 请问您本次来的目的是
Welcome to France. What is the purpose of your visit?
爱情
L'amour.
先生 请老实回答问题
Just answer the question, sir!
抱歉抱歉
Oh, I'm s-so sorry.
来办事...
Um, business...
办情事
of l'amour.
加点糖会顺口一点
It helps to add a little sugar...
克劳德兄
Claude.
谢谢 但其实...
Oh. Thank you, but th--
这个... 不是我的真名
this is, uh, not my real name.
是我的情圣第二人格
It's my romantic alter ego.
我是来给我老婆一个惊喜
I'm surprising my wife.
不错哦
Not bad.
以美国人的标准来说
For an American.
是吗 你能做到比我更深情吗
Oh, really? You can do better?
许多年以前 我在这间咖啡厅遇到一个女孩
Many years ago, I met a woman in this very cafe.
我们有过短暂但激烈的一段情缘
We had a brief but passionate affair,
白天我们一同探访了巴黎各处
spending our days exploring Paris
而在晚上
and our nights...
我们也探索对方身体各处
exploring each other.
我有一次曾带一个女人
Well, I-I once took a woman
去了迪士尼乐园与诺式莓果乐园
to both Disneyland and Knott's Berry Farm.
在同一天内
In the same day.
在我们分开的那一天
On the day we parted...
我们约定好会在这个情人节在此相见
we promised to meet here on this Valentine's Day
来重燃我们的爱火
to rekindle our love.
但谁知道呢
Who knows?
她记得这件事的几率非常...
The chances of her even remembering --
偶买噶
Oh, mon dieu.
-克莱尔 -克莱尔
- Claire! - Claire!
你好
Bonjour.
哈喽
Hello.
骚瑞 对不起
I'm -- I'm so sorry.
"骚瑞" 你怎么知道我懂英语呢
"Sorry"? H-How did you know I speak English?
祝您旅途愉快
Have a nice visit.
不好意西
Excusez-moi.
宰哪李...
Um... ou se trouve, um...
你想要去哪里
What are you looking for?
看蒙娜丽莎 去麦当劳
Mona Lisa? McDonald's?
都在那个方向
Both are that way.
先提醒你 我们法国这里餐点都是正常大小
Heads up, the portions here are normal-size.
你怎么知道我是美国人 我的口音有那么蹩脚吗
H-How did you know I'm American? Is my accent that bad?
我们穿着一样啊
We're dressed the same.
没需要这么人身攻击我吧
There's no reason to attack me.
杰在哪里
Hey. Where's Jay?
我觉得他好像紧张了
I think he's nervous.
他已经换了三次衣服
He has changed his outfit three times.
如果娶我的体验也是这样 那还真是不容易
If this is what it's like to be married to me, it's no picnic.
我们有个麻烦
We have a problem.
我得带你看个东西 跟我来
I have to show you something. Come here.
波尔·桑德斯
Burl Saunders!
很接近了 是厄尔·钱伯斯
Close. Earl Chambers.
得奖的人不是杰
Jay isn't getting the award.
他是来替他的前搭档厄尔领奖的人
He's accepting it on behalf of his ex-partner, Earl.
什么
What?
怎么会这样
How?
当博览会打来的时候
When the Expo called,
是曼尼负责跟他们交流的 因为他会说法语
Manny talked to them because he speaks French.
至少当时他是这么觉得的
At least, he thought he did.
我想解释 是因为法语的"酒店房间"
In my defense, the French word for "Hotel room"
听起来跟"钱伯"很像
sounds a lot like "Chamber."
是 是
Oh, oui, oui.
他们说要让你们住总统套房
They said you're putting you up in the royal suite.
以前好像是某个伯爵[厄尔]的房间
It used to be some earl's chamber.
我们衣柜界的人就是这样 格调就是高
That's closet people for you -- class all the way!
他来了 我们怎么做
Ah. He's here. What do we do?
什么都不做 跟他说实话
Nothing. Tell him the truth.
杰是个成年人了 他能承受
Jay's a grown man. He can handle it.
行 但如果他朝我喉咙攻过来了
Okay, but if he goes for my throat,
准备好打给"走 妖 妖"吧
be ready to dial neuf, un, un.
这个语言 就像是一群马在讲话
That language. It's like a bunch of horses talking.
看看这里 该来的都来了
Look at this place. Everybody's here.
柏林衣柜局的海因里希·穆勒
Heinrich Muler of Berlin Closet-stadt,
东京衣柜与罐装鲸鱼肉的苏珊·贞树
Susan Sadaki from Tokyo Closets and Canned Whale Meat.
衣柜界有头有脸的都来了
It's a regular who's who.
是啊 哪怕你说出了他们的名字 我还是对不上
Yeah, even when you say all their names.
我必须跟你说
You know, I gotta tell you,
这个奖真的是来得太及时了
this award couldn't have come at a better time.
在我失去衣柜公司后 有时我觉得
With my closet company gone, sometimes it feels like
我这一生并没有足以展现给人看的成就
I don't have anything to show for a lifetime of work,
仿佛我做过的一切都无足轻重
like it didn't matter.
但受到肯定我就知道不是了
But now I know it did.
是的
Yes.
在这里等我
Wait here.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
新计划 我要带他离开这里 我吸引他注意
New plan -- I'm getting him out of here, keeping him busy.
你去跟衣柜界的人谈
You go and talk to the closet people.
让他们把奖颁给他
Make them give him an award.
任何奖都行 他不会知道有何区别
Any kind of award. He won't know the difference.
-怎么做到 -贿赂啊
- How? - Bribe them.
黒函恐吓啊 色诱啊
Blackmail them. Seduce them.
我是没把你教好吗
Have I taught you nothing.
-菲尔 -克莱尔
- Phil? - Claire.
-克莱尔 -基
- Claire? - Guy?
天啊 你怎么会在这里
Oh, my God. What are you doing here?
克莱尔 你认识这"基"友吗
Claire, you know this Guy?
以前认识的啦
Well, um...I used to.
你们两个在这里做什么呢
What are you both doing here?
我来给你个情人节惊喜啊
I came to surprise you on Valentine's Day.
你记得你飞机上那个满脸绷带的人吗
You know the guy on the plane with all the face bandages?
那个人是我
That was me.
克莱尔 你难道忘了
Claire, do you not remember
你30年前跟我约好要在今日
asking me to meet you here in this cafe
在这个咖啡厅见面吗
exactly 30 years after we parted?
隐隐约约吧
Vaguely.
我真是疯了才会认为我有希望
I-I-I was crazy to think this could work out.
你这么美好的女人当然早就结婚了
Of course a woman as magnificent as you is married.
我并不想打扰你们浪漫的一天
I don't want to interfere with your day of romance.
我会独自一个人在我们的老地点徘徊
I will wander our old haunts alone
然后回我的酒店去
and return to my hotel
让如影随形的回忆将我包裹
in the ghostly embrace of our memories.
-再会 克莱尔 -行了 再见
- Adieu, Claire. - Okay, cool. Bye.
-是啊 -我们走
- Yeah. - Let's go.
好了 大日子 满满的日程
Alright, big day. Lots of plans.
第一件事 进入角色
First things first, getting into character.
克劳德·比克斯比
Claude Bixby,
芥末大亨 天赋异禀
mustard magnate with a flair for --
菲尔 克劳德
Uh, Phil -- Claude --
你这样大费周章我很开心
I-I love that you're doing all of this,
但就这样甩掉基
but doesn't some tiny part of you
你心里没有一点内疚吗
feel guilty for ditching Guy?
他都等了我30年呢
I mean, he did wait for me for 30 years.
我们可以邀请他一起喝杯红酒
We could invite him for a glass of wine.
好吧
Fine.
但我警告你 假如他越界
But I'm warning you, if he gets out of line,
克劳德会空手道
Claude knows karate.
还会以色列格斗术 他母亲是犹太血统
And Krav Maga. He's Jewish on his mother's side.
我们往这边走 去博物馆
Let's go this way, to the museum.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我觉得他们在等我回去
I think they're expecting me back inside.
让他们等
Make them wait.
你以为新娘为什么都最后入场
Why do you think the brides arrive after everyone else?
你就是新娘
You're the bride.
是啊 我是新娘
Yeah, I'm the bride.
-那好 我们 -不不不
- Alright, let's -- - No, no, no.
其实是这边
You know what? It's this side.
-明天 -不
- So, tomorrow -- - No, no!
抱歉 其实是这边
You know what? I'm sorry. It's this way.
逗我玩吗
Are you kidding me?!
怎么了
What?!
太美了
How beautiful!
你好
Bonjour.
B-Bonjour.
你好
Bonjour.
抱歉 不好意思
Pardon. Excusez-moi.
你好
Bonjour.
一位吗 先生
Une table pour un, monsieur?
克莱尔 还记得那次
Oh, Claire, remember that time
我们溜进了那家葡萄酒吧的酒窖
when we snuck into the cellar of that wine bar?
天哪 那时我们是那么年轻疯狂
Oh, God, we were so crazy and so young!
现在可不是了 你说什么 外婆
Not anymore. What's that, Grandma?
她已经当外婆了
She's a grandma now.
没有比生命创造生命更美的事了
Well, there's nothing more beautiful than a life creating life,
-反过来讲 -创造更多生命
- which in turn -- - Creates more life.
克莱尔和我该走了
Well, uh...Claire and I should get going.
我还想去圣心大教堂
I was hoping to get up to Sacre Coeur
眺望整座城市
to get a view of the whole city.
没必要
No need.
我在半岛酒店有露台花园套房
I have a rooftop garden suite at The Peninsula.
有全市最好的风景
It's the best view in town.
这太完美了
How perfect is this?
完美得令人泄气
Frustratingly!
好了 开始吧
Alright. Here we go.
让我看看
Let's see here.
你好
Bonjour.
几分钟后我会在广场表演
In a few minutes, I'm going to be performing in the square.
我叫菲茨宝
Je m'appelle Fizbo.
他才是菲茨宝
Lui, c'est Fizbeau.
-什么 -他才是菲茨宝
- What? - He is Fizbeau!
菲茨宝 知道吗
Fizbeau, okay?
基 套房太美了
Guy, this suite is so beautiful.
我记得上次我们在巴黎时
I think the last time we were in Paris,
连一法郎都要共享
we had a franc between the two of us.
老天 法郎又是哪个郎
Oh, God! Who's Frank?
我在生意场上很走运
I've been lucky in business,
情场就不走运了
less so in love.
我想我都因此变成工作狂了
I guess it's turned me into a workaholic.
我每周肯定要在办公室十到十二个小时
I must be in the office 10, 12 hours a week.
要喝些香槟吗
Shall we have some champagne?
不 谢了
Uh, no, thank you.
我真的没心情喝香槟
I'm not really in the mood for champagne.
那我们走运了 因为只有两个杯子
Lucky for us, because there are only two glasses.
请允许我来敬酒
Allow me to make a toast.
敬菲尔
To Phil.
敬他允许我与你共度这一点时光
For allowing me to spend a bit more time
我认识过的最慷慨的情人
with the most generous lover I've ever --
好了 你的小把戏我都看穿了
Okay! I see what you're doing here.
香槟 酒店套房 旋转木马
The champagne, the hotel suite, that carousel ride.
每次我转过来你俩就不笑了
You two stopped laughing every time I circled around.
抱歉 伙计 但这事没门
I'm sorry, buddy, but it's not gonna happen.
菲尔说得对 我已经结婚了
Phil's right. I'm a married woman.
这个旅途不会有任何浪漫韵事
There will be no romance on this trip.
抱歉 我真傻
I'm sorry. I've been a fool.
看来我有点纵容自己沉醉于幻想之中了
I guess I let myself indulge in a fantasy more than I should.
拜托 让我们假装这一切
Please, let us all pretend this...
从未发生过
never happened.
等等
Wait.
你用了普朗克误导
Was that Poulanc's misdirect?
没错
Indeed.
你也是魔术师吗
A fellow prestidigitator?
是的
Yes!
来握个手
Put her there.
您的手表 先生
Your watch, sir?
-在找这个吗 -什么
- Looking for this? - What?!
不可能
Oh, no way!
我们该走了
We should bounce.
告诉我 你们这次来一定会去
Tell me you're going to visit Le Musee des Magiciens
魔术师博物馆
while you're here.
The Museum of Magicians?
我想去想疯了 但他们在周五
I'm dying to go, but they're closed
周六周日 还有周一周三
Fridays, Saturdays, and Sundays --
都不开门
and Mondays and Wednesdays.
认识馆长就能进去
Not if you know the owner.
我能让我们进去私人参观
I can get us a private tour.
太好了
Sweet!
克莱尔 你怎么想
Claire, what do you say?
我们可以假装把你锯成两半
We can pretend to saw you in half.
或者真锯也行
Or just do it.
你好 打扰一下
Hello. Hi. Hi. Excuse me.
你为啥穿成这个样子
Why are you dressed like that?
冒牌货
Imposteur!
你是个冒牌货
Tu es un imposteur!
你是 你才是个冒牌祸呢
You're -- You're the imposteur...
如果这个词是我想的意思的话
if that word means what I think it means.
他偷走了菲茨宝
He'd stolen Fizbo.
我迷之错落的彩格
The whimsically mismatched plaids,
我标志性的一抹奔放腮红
my trademark bold splash of pink,
还有我的蓝色嘴唇
my blue lip!
他很明显看过我网上的小丑教程
He'd clearly seen one of my online clown tutorials!
各位 菲茨宝又和大家见面了
Hey, guys. Fizbo again.
记得上腮红时要轻轻一扫
Just remember when you're applying your rouge to go easy.
你是一个小丑 不是个荡妇
You're an Auguste clown, not a tramp.
把外套给我
You know what? Give me the jacket.
我
Oh! I --
我应该想到的
I should've seen that coming.
把你的手帕给我
Donne moi ce mouchoir!
干得好啊 先生
Touche, monsieur!
把我的假发还给我
You know what? Give me my wig.
就在这时 我想起来[被它击中]了
And that's when it hit me.
《欧洲小丑》
"The Clowns of Europe."
我十几岁的时候买到的
I got this when I was a teenager.
它就是我的青春
It was my "Sergeant Pepper's."
打开封皮 是一个又一个的小丑
Clown after clown pushing the envelope,
包括菲茨寶
including Fizbeau.
繁体寶
B-e-a-u!
我还以为是我创造的角色 但他是对的
Here, I thought I'd come up with the idea, but he was right.
我才是冒牌祸
I was the imposteur.
如果我没记错那个词的话
If that's the word.
我高中的语言课
For my high school language requirement,
我选修了拍卖语言
I took auction-calling.
拿破仑的墓好壮观啊
See, isn't Napoleon's tomb spectacular?
我先说好 我离世的时候不需要这些
Just so you know, when I go, I-I don't need all this.
看 那不是曼尼吗
Look. That's Manny over there.
不不
No, no.
我去叫他
I'll go get him.
怎么样
How did it go?
他们会给杰颁奖吗
Are they giving Jay an award?
不会 他们说这会开创一个不好的先例
No. They said it would set a very dangerous precedent.
用标准的英语说的
And in perfect English.
看来这场蹩脚法语的误会
Turns out this whole misunderstanding
本来是完全可以避免的
was completely avoidable.
我们得想个办法
We need to figure out something.
可不能让杰发现
Jay can never find out
得奖的是厄尔而不是他
that Earl got an award instead of him.
哇
Wow.
看这里
Look at this place.
这样的工艺 这样的建筑
The craftsmanship, the architecture.
据说这个穹顶能起到耳语室的作用
They say the domed ceiling acts as a whisper chamber.
耳语室是什么意思啊
What does "whisper chamber" mean?
意思是我听到了你们刚刚说的
It means I heard everything you just said.
我平时得把电视机音量调高到40
I have to turn my TV up to 40,
但你俩的对话是又清晰又响亮
but that was loud and clear!
谢谢
Ah. Merci.
融入进去很简单嘛
It was easy to fit in.
我要做的不过是穿好点 再装腔作势点
All I had to do was look good and have a lot of attitude.
巴黎其实就像个巨大的同性恋酒吧
Paris was just like one big gay bar.
来啦
Et voila.
你的鸽子 先生
Votre pigeon, monsieur.
"鸽子"
"Pigeon"?
特色菜
Notre specialite.
祝您有个好胃口
Ah. Bon appetit.
好
Yah.
不 我做不到
No. I can't -- I can't do it.
我做不到 我不是法国人
I can't do it. I'm not French.
我不吃这种东西
And I-I'm not eating that.
这破围巾快逼疯我了
This scarf is driving me crazy!
打扰一哈...
E-Excusez-moi --
芝士汉堡在那边
Cheeseburger, that way.
很棒 谢谢啦
Cool. Thanks, man!
他们用那些古老的魔杖变出那么多魔术
It's amazing how much magic they got
真是太让人震惊了
out of those old wands.
现在 魔术师变魔术要简单多了
Today, magicians have it so easy, you know?
是的
Oh, yeah.
感觉到了分开的时刻了
Well, this basically feels like a natural breaking point,
至少对我来说是
for me, at least.
菲尔和我该 你懂的
Uh, Phil and I should probably you know?
当然 但我们的票
If you must, but our tickets
也能让我们进自动化博物馆
also get us to Le Musee des Automates.
它们就像机器人 但非常初级的
They're like robots, but very primitive.
基本上什么也不做
They basically do nothing.
就像我用汽车排烟管改造的那个吗
Um, like the one I built out of old mufflers?
我们能去吗 克莱尔
Can we, Claire?
是啊 我们能去吗克莱尔
Oh, yes, can we, Claire?
对不起
Excuse me.
歌洛莉亚 怎么了
Hey, Gloria. What's up?
我遇到难题了
I have a problem.
我也是
Yeah, so do I.
才发现我貌似喜欢宅男
Apparently, I'm into nerds.
是杰
It's Jay.
得奖人不是他
He's not getting that award.
什么
What?!
是我们误会了
It was some kind of mistake,
然后他发现这事 现在我们找不到他了
he found out, and now we can't find him.
天啊 我马上过去
Oh, my God. Okay, I-I'll be right there.
你确定没事吗
Are you sure it's okay?
绝对没事
Uh, yeah, it's more than okay.
你怎么找到我的
H-How did you find me?
你穿得很显眼啊
Well, you're pretty easy to spot.
对不起 我反应过度了
Look, I-I'm sorry I overreacted, okay?
如果你想扮菲茨宝 那就扮菲茨宝吧
If you want to be Fizbo, be Fizbo.
我再也不能扮菲茨宝了
I can never be Fizbo again.
菲茨宝已死
Fizbo is dead.
天啊 你这个人还真是善变
Oh, you're a moving target.
我今天遇见正牌菲茨宝了
Look, I ran into the real Fizbo today,
他朝我脸上喷水
and he squirted me in the face with water
还用书打我头了
and hit me in the head with a book.
什么
What?!
你看 我以为是我发明了
See, here, I thought I had created
这个奇妙独特的角色
this special, unique thing,
但其实多年以来 我就是个剽窃的骗子
but I'm the one that's been a fraud all this time!
我要把这套小丑服扔河里
I'm throwing the suit in the river!
等等
Wait.
那样算乱丢垃圾 这边有垃圾桶
That's littering. There's a trash can right over here.
等等啦
Wait!
我必须要说...
Look, I-I gotta say, um --
我不觉得你有剽窃任何东西
I don't -- I don't think you stole anything.
你这是什么意思
What do you mean?
你看 你说他用书打了你的头
Well, you said he hit you in the head with a book.
但我以为菲茨宝只为人带来欢乐
I mean, I thought Fizbo was all about joy.
是啊 他就是儿童般纯真的化身
He is. He's the embodiment of childlike innocence.
这就对了
Exactly.
-菲茨宝绝对不会使用暴力 -绝不
- Fizbo would never resort to violence. - Ever.
那家伙感觉一点都不像菲茨宝
This guy doesn't sound like Fizbo to me.
可是他看起来绝对是
Well, he sure looked like him.
菲茨宝绝对不只是鞋子特大号
Fizbo's more than just a-a pair of big shoes
还穿着完全不性感夹克的人
and an...un-sexy jacket.
他是一种思想
He -- He's an idea.
我今天学到的一件事
If I've learned anything today,
那就是造就人的不是衣装
it's that clothes do not make the man...
衣装也不造就小丑
or the clown.
你才是真正的菲茨宝
And you are the real Fizbo.
你是真心的吗
You mean it?
事实就是如此
I know.
走嘛
Now, come on.
我们一起去享受巴黎 今天可是情人节
Let's enjoy Paris. It's Valentine's Day.
走吧
Come on.
你这身帅气衣服是哪里弄来的
Where did you get this crazy get-up?
人家会盯着我们看的啦
People are gonna stare.
机器人博物馆中你最喜欢的是哪一部分
So...what was your favorite part of the robot museum?
我的妈呀
Oh, man.
太难选了 你先说
I can't decide. You go first.
我说完你就会抄我的
No, you'll just copy me.
我的确会
I'll do that.
那我们就同时间一起说吧
Well, let's, uh, let's just say it at the same time.
数到三
On three.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
-机械猴子乐队 -机械猴子乐队
- The mechanical monkey band. - The mechanical monkey band.
-异口同声 -异口同声
- Le jinx! - Jinx!
双重异口同声
Double jinx.
给两位
Pour vous deux.
天啊 是一幅画
O-Oh, my God. It's a painting!
画了我们
Of us!
谢谢
Merci.
-谢谢 -谢啦
- Merci beaucoup. - Merci.
我的手是不是搭着你的手
Is my...hand on yours?
是啊 但是... 我们没有这么做吧
Yeah, but I-I don't... think we did that.
这个... 我是时候回去找克莱尔了
Well, um, I better -- better go find Claire.
当然啦 是的
Of course. Yes.
感觉怪怪的 但我们是时候说再见了
Okay. W-Weird. I guess this is goodbye.
这个... 这个你拿去吧
You -- You should have this.
你收着吧
Keep it.
30年后再拿来给我
You'll give it to me in 30 years.
在约定的咖啡店相会
In our cafe.
我一定到
I'll be there.
再会了 基
Au revoir... Guy.
我问了歌洛莉亚
I talked to Gloria.
就觉得能在这里找到你
Thought I might find you here.
太可惜了 圣母院
It's a shame, Notre Dame.
那场大火
The fire.
是啊
Yeah.
想当年它是多么了不起啊
It used to be so impressive back in its day.
现在也还是很了不起啊
It's still pretty impressive.
空有壳而没有灵魂了
Just a shell of its former self.
最好的年头已随火而去
Best days are behind it.
再也回不到从前了
It'll never be the same.
虽然经受一些风雨 但它还是屹立不摇啊
It's taken some hits, but it's still standing,
而那... 可是勇气与毅力
and that's -- that's grit.
也正是那种精神激励了人们
That's what inspires people.
我也被这精神所激励
That's what inspires me.
真的是丢死人了
It's so embarrassing.
一大家子大老远跑来
The whole reason the family's here
就是为了见证我拿到那个破奖
is to see me get that damn award.
老爸
Oh, Dad!
整个家族里 只有我跟你在乎衣柜
You and I are the only ones in this family who care about closets.
大家会来 是因为我们都爱你
We're here because we love you.
来嘛
Come on.
一起去准备好吃这顿晚饭吧
Let's go get ready for that dinner.
在一个行业中奋斗45年是很长的一段时间
45 years is a long time to spend in one industry,
我也达成过许多成就
and I've accomplished a lot.
静声铰链为全美无数的卧室带来宁静
The whisper hinge brought serenity to the American bedroom.
我的发光门把为黑暗中更衣掀起革命
My glow knobs revolutionized getting dressed in the dark.
我还领衔主导了
And I led the charge
鞋架倾斜角度的标准制定
to standardize the angle of shoe racks.
不过我一生中最让我感到自豪的...
But the thing that I'm -- that I'm proudest of...
是我的家庭
is my family.
谢谢你们陪我来
Thank you for being here.
我爱你们大家
I love you all.
你们就是我的终身成就奖
You're my lifetime achievement award.
-谢谢你 老爸 -谢谢你的夸奖
- Oh! Thanks, Dad. - That's so sweet.
我们也爱你
We love you, too.
我们爱你 杰
We love you, Jay.
克莱尔·普里契特
Claire Pritchett?
让·卢克
Jean-Luc?!
我大学在这里时过得十分逍遥啊
I had a lot of fun here in college.
你怎么在这里
What are you doing here?
这是我丈夫
This is my husband.